Hi, in this lesson we compare a different ways to work with AI.
Now we will use the mix approach with plan design and details to get the best result.
This means we will provide both the UI's and short and the required functionality.
And then we will hit hopcopilot to create a clear plan, the development one before writing
any code.
This will help us build faster our application while still keeping the project clean
and correct.
So let me first explain why planning matters.
Because many developers jump into coding too early.
Without a plan up can be messy and hard to maintain or even require full arrives.
A short planning steps help AI understand the full feature and keeps the code organized
from the beginning.
Also it gives you a possibility to change the plan to adopt your needs to add some details
and the update will build more fits your expectations.
At the moment I am recording this video and hit hopcopilot doesn't release a plan mode.
But they should have it's own and for now I will show you how to create a plan using
ask mode in hit hopcopilot and then build the app following this plan.
It gives the plan mode already released you can use a simpler prompt.
I also prepared and you can find it in a lesson with materials and prompts.
And then you will be much easier to create a plan following this feature.
But you will use the ask mode to create a plan and the prompt will be a bit longer.
Just describe that we need some to do.
We need some to think about the structure and etc.
Let's generate a plan first of all switch to ask mode and I will go to paste my prompt.
You can also find it in the prompts and materials lesson of the prompt is I ask a pilot
to create a structured built plan for calculator up based on provided screenshot.
So I will provide a screenshot.
At the previous screenshot I can't click at context and find how to upload an image but
the easier way will be just open my folder where you have a screenshot and just move it
right here and the screenshot uploaded.
So and I ask using with template, with React and TypeScript.
I also ask follow clean architecture and reusable component patterns.
Split logic in the components and utilities were appropriate.
Use clear consistent name and for your best practices.
So I already ask a pilot think about architecture, don't create anything in one file.
Just split an file on logic so make it maintainable and reusable.
So there are some requirements.
The first one is one display at the top.
I will show you the screenshot or we have this calculator.
We have a top display and then we have agreed with buttons and I say that the button
grid 4 on 5 so we have 4 columns and 5 rows and I mention the reach buttons we have
just to be sure a pilot implement exactly what I want.
Then explain that I'd like to have simple CSS with centered cart layout and clean minimal
design.
So I also mention the output so I'd like to have a steps, a list of 5, 6 short to do's,
how a pilot will implement the plan.
The projects set up, some commands to create projects that it will share it with me.
I understand it will use the width so it will be definitely the React and TypeScript.
As I ask it to provide the file structure, list over usable part and logic, separation
for the components, delete these, maybe some hooks, constance, etc.
And I also ask to return all the plan as one code block or mark the smart down text.
You will see in a minute what I mean.
And please be sure you have an ask mode just to have just that the pilot doesn't start
to write any code for you and just provide you.
Output so I then start it.
Okay, it uses a screenshot to see reference, you see a lot of the way to be, you will generate
is organizing the code structure so we can see it.
And now we have a plan so you see this is a one code block with a plan.
We might see here as, if you'd like to open this plan you can click.
This button, apply in a data and you can read it so let me, you can read it, you can,
okay.
As the steps, can follow the width project, create reusable UI components so we already
say we have a display component, the key buttons, the icon button, key part, heart.
So if you implement the logic and composable hope utilities, you already provide the utilities
you have.
Okay, the button actions, menu of CSS, then some tests, then this is the performance to create
project, the command to create width project or the also command to install some additional
dev pool, this is the file structure as if you have the constants, some buttons, I guess
it, the symbols of the buttons we mentioned, we have also components, the card, display,
key part, etc.
We have some hooks, we have utils, we have tie-ups and we have some styles, what is good.
I also mentioned some responsibilities and architecture models, it would would business logic
use details in the whole scope, all the rules inside the scope later, oh yeah.
As the buttons layout, he just again repeated, we mean most CSS guidelines, example constants
for the buttons, so we see we have all the buttons, we have the label.
We have the idea for the button to easier identify it and we have some of them from control
components, some of them are just digits, some of them are operators like and divide multiply
and depending on the type you use a different functions and also some tests, so you can save
the file, for example, if you click keep, you'll be able to save the file, let me save
it, for example, you know, under projects folder and say go, wait or up, when, I click save,
okay, it was save it and in the next lesson, we will build an application following this
plan, okay, see you.